stop scrolling I know you are here you
want to speak English you have been
crying for months years but still when
it times to speak your mind goes blank
you
hesitate hi everyone my name is shalima
and welcome back to my another session
of learning English and improving your
English speaking skills with me so guys
today is day one of our 30-day spoken
English course and I'm here to help you
to speak English fluently and
confidently yes of course confidently
and this course is designed for you
especially whether you are a beginner or
someone who wants to improve their
English speaking skills by the end of 30
days you will see a big difference in
your way to speak English fluent so let
me ask you a question do you struggle to
speak in
English today I'll give you two powerful
rules that will help you to start
speaking English
immediately and the biggest problem in
learning spoken English is because most
of people think speaking English is
difficult because they worry too much
about grammar rules but the truth is you
don't need to learn complicated grammar
to speak English you don't need to
memorize thousands of words so today all
your problems ends and today you will
start speaking English with confidence
and you will need our just two Simple
Rules so these two rules will change the
way you speak English forever so guys no
boring grammar no memorizing long
vocabulary list just two simple formulas
that you can use
immediately so before we begin let me
tell you exactly what you will learn in
today's lesson in day one because this
series is going on till day of 30 okay
so here I'm going to tell you what you
will learn in today's lesson I'll tell
you two golden rules that will help you
to start speaking English I'll tell you
real life conversation using rules
common mistakes people make and how to
avoid them and five new vocabulary words
that will improve your daily
communication and a special Challenge
and homework that will help you to
practice what you learn and here is
something special also because every
single day for next 30 days I'll give
you five new vocabulary words and by the
end of this course you will have 150
plus new words in your vocabulary so
sound
exciting let's begin all
right so here guys first of of all
before beginning and before telling you
anything let me ask you a question have
you been in a situation where you wanted
to speak English but suddenly your uh
brain froze maybe in an interview maybe
in front of friends maybe when someone
asked you a simple question in English
and at that moment you felt
embarrassed you knew what you wanted to
say but the words didn't come out
you felt ashamed you thought maybe
English is not for me you felt like
giving up but wait let me tell you
something no one else will speaking
English is not about intelligence
speaking English is not about learning
difficult grammar speaking English is
about
practice and confidence and today I will
give you a
shortcut just two simple rules that will
help you to start speaking English
immediately on day one I wanted to give
you something which really help you
right so are you guys ready for that if
you ready please let me know in the
comment section so now guys let's begin
I'll share you two rules for speaking
English think about this every day you
do two types of Works got got it every
day you do two types of work some work
is happening right now you know the
action which is going you know ongoing
action some work is already finished
that means the action has been
completed and for these we only need two
rules okay because I would like to tell
you in our daily conversation we only
use two rules these two rules to speak
English faster so rule number one I am
plus ing form you know for work which is
happening right now rule number two I
have plus third form for work that is
finished all right that's it two rules
if you understand this you can start
speaking English right now now for
instance there are few examples okay so
I am learning English all right I am
watching this video okay English I'm
watching this video I'm improving my
speaking
skills now guys repeat after me I am
practicing English every day I am
getting better at
speaking okay I am improving my English
I am speaking with
confidence how is it cool now guys you
will have to try make try making your
own sentences okay for example I am Dash
Dash Okay think of an action and you are
whatever you are doing right now okay
let's learn I have plus verbs third form
because this is used for completed
action with a connection to the present
okay for instance let me give you the
examples I have learned a new rule today
okay I have started my English Journey
started is a third form I have spoken in
English before so spoken is a third form
all right and you will have to use I
have plus verbs third form now repeat
after me I have completed this
lesson I have improved my speaking
skills now guys you will have to make
sentences using I have have dash dash
you will have to think something that
you have done today okay and leave the
comment now repeat after me it is a kind
of Shadow practice okay I am practicing
English every day I'm getting better at
speaking I have started my English
Journey okay I have understood this
Rule now let's practice together I will
ask you a question and you will answer
using today's two rules okay so the
question is what are you doing right now
and you have to give me the answer using
I am plus ing form either you can pause
this video or you can uh write a comment
all right now the next question is what
you have learned today by using I have
plus verbs third form okay now say your
answer out loud don't worry about about
your mistakes just try so guys now let's
start with the real life conversation
using these two Simple Rules suppose you
are talking to your friend okay your
friend called you and you pick the phone
and you say hey what are you doing so
you say I'm watching a video to improve
my English then your friend say wow have
you learned something new so you say yes
I have learned two powerful rules
today how is it okay next scenario
suppose you are at a job interview okay
so interviewer ask you tell me about
your
experience so you will tell I have
worked as a sales executive for 3 years
now again interviewer asks you what are
you doing now so you will tell I'm
improving my English to grow in my
career
how is it is it cool okay let's go
scenario number three you are at a
restaurant and ordering a food so waiter
waiter is asking for you are you ready
to order so you will say yes I'm looking
at the menu so viter again ask you have
you decided what to eat then you will
reply yes I have chosen a pasta dish now
imagine this situation in your life and
try using these sentences in real life
conversation all right so now uh let me
tell you some common mistakes like
people made in Daily conversations right
so you not do all these things yes if
you if you're saying I am completed my
work that is wrong I have completed my
work I have going to the market that is
wrong I am going to the market that is
correct
now as I promised here are five powerful
words you can use today okay so first of
all the word is enhance enhance is a
verb and it means to improve or make
better for example I am enhancing my
English
skills number two word number two is
achieve this is also a verb that means
to succeed in reaching a goal for
example
I have achieved fluency in
English now word number three observe
this is also a verb that means to watch
or notice something okay for instance I
am observing how native speakers talk
now word number four is confident that
is adjective means feeling sure of
yourself okay for example I Have Become
more confident in speaking English word
number five word number five so word
number five is implement this is also a
verb that means to put an idea into
action okay for instance implementing
these rules in my daily life okay now
guys you will have to write sentences in
the comment section so here I would like
to give a challenge challenge for
speaking one minute using these two
rules all right so first of all you have
to record yourself and saying five
sentences with I am plus ing all right
and second one is record yourself saying
five sentences with I have plus verbs
third form all right and post your
practice in the comment or you can do
the practice in front of the camera or
in front of the mirror all right and if
you will comment me then I'll read your
comment and give a shout out in my next
video Okay now what's
next what you will learn tomorrow in day
two that I'm going to tell you okay so
tomorrow we will learn tricky rules to
frame sentences easily and how to use
model verbs to express yourself better
how to speak confidently in daily life
situations okay and of course five new
daily words all right so guys if you are
interested and if you want to speak your
engl and if you want to improve your
speaking skills with me then definitely
stay with me till 30 days because in
next 30 days I'm going to teach you new
things I'll give you the new exercises
I'll give you the new tricks I'll give
you the new rules I'll give you the
tricky rules to improve your English
without you know going to going in a
deep
grammar all right so if you really want
to improve your English stay with me
till next 30 days so from uh day two
because uh if you like this video okay
if you like this video then definitely
I'll make day two video okay for you so
if if you give a lot of likes if you if
you share this video if I get a good
views on this video then definitely I'll
continue this series till next 30 days
all right so congratulations you have
completed day one of this course all
right learning doesn't stop here your
homework for today is write and say five
sentences with I am plus ing form okay
write five sentences with I have plus
third form okay and practice speaking
them out loud either you can write the
sentences in the comment box so I can
check whether it is correct or or it is
wrong or you can write it down on your
journal on your notebook or you can do
the practice in front of mirror or you
can record yourself now let's let me
give you for more examples I am drinking
water I have finished my homework
remember practice makes progress and the
more you speak the better you become all
right speaking English is not about
being perfect it's about being confident
so don't be afraid of making mistakes
mistakes means you are learning am I
right so if you practice these two
Simple Rules every day you will start
speaking English naturally and
fluently so guys keep practicing and
I'll see you in day two with another
exciting
lesson so if you found this lesson
helpful please like this video and share
this video to other who wants to speak
English okay so if you like my video
please give thumbs up and don't forget
to subscribe my channel so thanks for
watching bye-bye take care